{"tossups": [{"question": "This man became greatly angry when he found his firstborn had slept with his concubine Bilhah. He gradually claimed the majority of his uncle\u2019s flock of sheep and goats and married two of his daughters. This man was born grabbing the heel of his twin brother, a redheaded hunter who was tricked into bequeathing his birthright to his man. For ten points, name this son of Isaac whose descendants formed the tribes of Israel.", "answer": "<b> Jacob</b> (accept<b> Israel</b> until mentioned)", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Ken Khachigian, this President\u2019s chief speechwriter, penned an apology speech for this man to deliver at Bergen-Belsen following his involvement in the Bitburg controversy. This man\u2019s doctor replied \u201cToday, Mr. President, we are all Republicans\u201d after he survived an assassination attempt conducted by John Hinckley. This former President of the Screen Actors\u2019 Guild was succeeded in office by his Vice President, George H.W. Bush. For ten points, name this conservative U.S. President who led during much of the 1980s.", "answer": "Ronald<b> Reagan</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "These people established a kingdom centered around Toulouse until they were forced out of France in the Battle of Vouille. The execution of the general Stilicho allowed these people to win a war against the weakened forces of Honorius. The emperor Valens was slain at Adrianople fighting against these people, who sacked Rome in 410 AD under the rule of Alaric. For ten points, name these Germanic peoples whose name implies that they came from the West.", "answer": "<b> Visigoths</b> (prompt on Goths; prompt on Germanic people)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "This man pondered a quote from the<em> Baghavad Gita</em>, \u201cNow I am become Death, the destroyer of worlds,\u201d at the successful Trinity test. For ten points, name this head of the Los Alamos lab during World War II\u2019s Manhattan Project.", "answer": "Julius Robert<b> Oppenheimer</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "For ten points, give this surname of an Ohio Senator who sponsored an early Antitrust Act and of General William Tecumseh.", "answer": "<b> Sherman</b> (accept James<b> Sherman</b>, John<b> Sherman</b>, William (Tecumseh)<b> Sherman</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Rain and this resource were mythologically provided to Wagadu by a black snake called Bida until a young man cut off its head. The \u201csilent trade\u201d often exchanged salt for this resource, which names an African colony that gained independence from Britain in 1957. When Mansa Musa traveled the Hajj, he distributed so much of this resource in Cairo that its prices remained depressed for many years. For ten points, name this precious metal once mined in the soil of Ghana.", "answer": "<b> gold</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "One work by this artist shows a man being attacked by owl-like demons, part of his<em> Los Caprichos</em> series. This artist created a series of etchings of gruesome scenes following Napoleon\u2019s invasion of his home country in the Peninsular War. In his old age, this artist began a series of paintings on the walls of his home, including one of<em> Saturn Devouring His Son</em>. For ten points, name this Spanish artist who painted an execution scene in<em> The Third of May, 1808</em>.", "answer": "Francisco<b> Goya</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "A group created to perform this action was founded by Abraham Woodhull, who used the name Samuel Culper. While performing this action, Robert Townsend discovered a shipment of paper that British printers intended to turn into counterfeit bills. After being arrested while performing this action, one man stated \u201cI regret I have but one life to lose for my country.\u201d A \u201ctailor\u2019s apprentice\u201d performs this action in the musical<em> Hamilton</em>. For ten points, name this action performed by Nathan Hale with the goal of reporting British troop movements.", "answer": "<b> spy</b>ing for the United States", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "George Gay survived this battle, the only member of Torpedo Squadron Eight to do so. Dauntless dive bombers were used at this battle, in which the<em> Mikuma</em> and<em> Akagi</em> were lost. The naval code JN-25 was broken shortly before this battle, in which the<em> Hornet</em> and<em> Enterprise</em> provided air support. The <em>Yorktown</em> and four Japanese carriers were sunk in, for ten points, what 1942 battle, considered to be the turning point in the Pacific theater of World War II?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Midway</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In this country, vassals pleged themselves to their lords through contracts called manrents. One leader of this kingdom lost the Battle of Falkirk after his schiltron formations proved useless against archers and joined with Andrew Moray to win the Battle of Stirling Bridge. Edward Longshanks executed this country\u2019s national hero, William Wallace, in 1305 during its war for independence. For ten points, name this country that signed the 1706 Treaty of Union to join with its southern neighbor, England.", "answer": "<b> Scotland</b> (do not accept England or Great Britain or the United Kingdom)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This city was ruled by a council of nine men called the Signoria, headed by a Gonfaloniere of Justice. In the Battle of Montaperti, Siena\u2019s Ghibellines defeated this city\u2019s Guelphs. Supporters of the Pope plotted the Pazzi Conspiracy to overthrow this city\u2019s ruling family. Valuable objects were burned by a preacher from this city, Savonarola, during the Bonfire of the Vanities. This city\u2019s rulers included Cosimo the Great, who used his banking wealth to sponsor artists like Donatello. For ten points, name this center of the Renaissance, an Italian city ruled by the Medici.", "answer": "<b> Florence</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "In this country, 15,000 soldiers deliberately slowed their pace to capture a castle garrisoned by only 500 troops, thus securing victory for a clan in a 1600 battle. The motto \u201cenrich the country, strengthen the military\u201d was used by a government in this nation to promote industrialization; that government put down the Satsuma Rebellion. For ten points, name this imperial Asian nation which underwent the Meiji Restoration.", "answer": "<b> Japan</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A former hotel in this state, the Royal Poinciana, was once the largest wooden building in the world. A city in this state became the largest by area in the contiguous USA when it consolidated with Duval County in 1968. A railroad along this state\u2019s eastern coast was developed by Henry Flagler; that railway\u2019s southernmost portion is now the Overseas Highway to Key West. For ten points, name this southern state, home to Jacksonville and Miami.", "answer": "<b> Florida</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "A poem addressed to this person imagines \u201cA crown, a mansion, and a throne that shine, / With gold unfading\u201d and begins by describing a \u201cCelestial choir! enthron\u2019d in realms of light.\u201d An anecdote-filled biography of this man was written by Parson Weems in 1800; that biography claims that, at the age of six, this man could not tell a lie when asked if he cut down a cherry tree. For ten points, name this first president of the United States.", "answer": "George<b> Washington</b> (accept \u201c(To) His Excellency General<b> Washington</b>\u201d)", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Poetry"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This country was blamed for the shelling of Mainila, a false flag operation that ended a non-aggression pact. Less than a year after that war ended, aggression against this country resumed in the (+) Continuation War. This country was defended by the Mannerheim line, from which soldiers tossed Molotov cocktails at the Red Army. The (*) </b> Soviet Union was expelled from the League of Nations in December 1939 after it invaded, for ten points, what Scandinavian country in the Winter War?", "answer": "<b> Finland</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man offered his home nation as a potential trial location for the Lockerbie</b> <b>bombers. Inspired by a Chilean effort, this leader established a Truth (+)</b> <b>and</b> <b>Reconciliation Commission in 1996 to investigate and provide some amnesty for past human rights abuses. This man declared that he was \u201cprepared to die\u201d during the (*) </b>Rivonia Trial, in which his role within the militant Spear of the Nation led him to be imprisoned for 27 years, mostly on Robben Island. For ten points, name the first black president of South Africa.", "answer": "Nelson<b> Mandela </b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}